<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KUALI</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://kualistories.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kualistories.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 15:40:10 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 15:40:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conversations with Jason Lee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/university.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;university&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us what does Biomedical Engineering entail at Imperial?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s mostly engineering-related material. You do modules from nearly every department, such as Chemistry, Mechanical Engineering, Computer Science, Physics, Electrical and Electronics Engineering, and etc. You can choose your stream in your third year, and focus on Mechanical, Electrical, or Bioengineering. For me, the most interesting and practical subjects were the Computer Science and programming as these are used a lot in other areas as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflecting on your university experience, what did you learn?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I actually found both the university and the course slightly unsuitable for me. It was a really dry and research-oriented field, which is not what I want to involve myself in; I find myself being drawn more to fields such as application design and not so much engineering. Now I’m studying Information Systems as part of my course in NTU (Nanyang Technological Institute) and I’m enjoying it a lot more as it enables me to interact more with more interesting fields such as sociology and psychology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh that’s interesting. Would you say it’s because you didn’t research the course well enough before going into Imperial College? Or was it something else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I would say I did my research pretty thoroughly before entering; my main attraction to the course was actually to involve myself in doing interesting stuff but the heavy focus on research really wasn’t a good fit for me. This is my personal opinion, but I find the lecturers also kind of taught for the sake of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…they really take the time to get to know us and enrich our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m enjoying my time here (in Singapore) much more as we have very thought-provoking discussions and the lecturers are quite passionate about teaching, they really take the time to get to know us and enrich our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect is that coming out of research, the job prospects are really not that abundant especially in the business sector; that isn’t to say that the whole course is bad, it does cover a very broad range of topics like Computer Science and coding. Just bear in mind that you really should consider your job prospects after university as (in my case) out of the 10+ Malaysians and Singaporeans that came out of the field, only one went on to do biomedical-related work while the rest exited the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about living in the United Kingdom? How was your “London experience”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Travel a lot and take all the time you need to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed living in the United Kingdom actually. My advice to younger students would be to make full use of your time here, and get to know people of the same interest! Travel a lot and take all the time you need to do so; you’ll rarely have time after you start working. In terms of travelling, I would highly recommend Iceland, especially since I love the outdoors and nature in general, Iceland is really awesome for that! Spain as well, the food there is extremely good and cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/iceland.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iceland&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially during my first year at university, I felt really scared of trying new stuff alone; I would say you should just dive in head first and try new things. Perhaps something outside of Msoc (Malaysian Society) would be good; I personally enjoyed the Funkology club at Imperial College as I feel they’re extremely friendly towards outsiders and are really nice people in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any major regrets about your university life?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I would say not joining Funkology in my first year, haha. Another one would be that I didn’t get the option to explore courses outside of my degree; I would have loved the chance to explore liberal arts, psychology, and film. Sadly, these aren’t available to an engineering student. The Imperial Horizons program does mitigate that to a certain extent, however I would really like to explore them in depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you elaborate more on what you’re studying now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/technical.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;technical&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m currently studying about Information Systems. Information Systems is the more practical side of Computer Science. Computer Science focuses more on the technical aspects and building algorithms, which I’m not interested in, whereas Information System focuses more on applying the knowledge, how to manage it properly, the impacts of it in relation to business, society and etc. You can choose different areas to focus on, from management, design and user experience, and more technical stuff such as data mining. Hence, it’s a system of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say the United States or Singapore are very good places to study this field. I personally chose to study in Singapore, and I’m quite glad as I’m doing something I like and find useful in the future. One thing I found is that people who are doing their Masters in Singapore are mostly working people; they mainly do it to gain additional qualifications and not immediately after they finish their Bachelor’s unlike in the United Kingdom, United States and other places where students usually continue doing their Master’s directly after graduating from undergraduate studies. I think this is definitely something to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks Jason! Hope to hear from you soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/15/Conversations-with-Jason-Lee/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/15/Conversations-with-Jason-Lee/</guid>
        
        <category>university</category>
        
        <category>regret</category>
        
        <category>academic</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going Off the Deep End</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of university are very different from high school. In high school or college, there was a defined set of targets and expectations put forward by others, for instance scoring well in school exams, looking for scholarship opportunities, entering a good university etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In university, you are on your own. You are responsible for every decision you make and every decision you make might decide who you are and what you do in the very near future. One major difference I noticed lies in the absence of short-term goals like what you would have during high school. You know you have to do something but what? How? I felt lost and perhaps depressed, to a certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Lost1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lost&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first entered university, I actually felt that the language and culture barrier was a factor that hindered social mingling, which was quite surprising to me. I assumed that it would go okay but I found it a bit challenging to mingle with the locals. To be frank, I found the local accent quite hard to understand; I connected better with international students and we knew how each other felt, since we were all trying our best to communicate and learn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the language and cultural barriers, I struggled a little in making deeper connections with people, even though I had no problem doing so back in Malaysia, but it did get better eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously I also felt lost as I was questioning what was the point of studying so hard in university. “What’s the next step?” I wondered, especially since I could see the end of university coming soon, and with that, there was a need to “step into society” and do something worthwhile as a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Due to the language and cultural barriers, I struggled a little in making deeper connections with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my second and third year, I felt a lot more comfortable. I eventually started some projects and a business of my own, which was quite ironic as I used to hate business. The financial pressure as a result of my business, the amount of workload from both study and work as well as personal health issues made me feel quite down in the dumps at a certain point. Some would say “depressed” although I’m not really sure if the symptoms fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this was the path I chose and I never regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-going-off-the-deep-end/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-going-off-the-deep-end/</guid>
        
        <category>university</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entrepreneurship from Scratch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my second and third year, I started a few projects as well as some business endeavors. It was a tremendously exhausting journey but surprisingly I felt much better than I was in first year.  I found a path and a purpose, though it might not be the easiest path to walk on. I might trip or fall a lot but even if I do, I am moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some might say university is “useless” because in many cases, what you study will probably have nothing to do with what you do in the future. Personally, I think that university is the perfect ground for you to build connections with amazing people all around the world and the perfect ground to fail. Yes, fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a university student, you do not have as many responsibilities and expectations than you would have as a working adult but you have more freedom and help. You can afford to fail and start over - an inevitable yet crucial process that builds you up to your eventual success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, you have an easy access to a network of professionals literally right at your doorstep! Professors and lecturers are generally always willing to help you if they can with free advice if you go up to them for a chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you elaborate more on the business that you started? I think it’d be helpful to give a glimpse at what is possible for them to accomplish even during their uni studying period.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a social enterprise with my business partner in Malaysia and recruited a few of my friends to join the team. The essence of a social entrepreneurship is building a business that gives back to the community, which I personally feel quite strongly about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you have no experience and no capital to do stuff, you need to get them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very rough in the beginning, especially when looking for investments or partnerships, as no one wants to support a company with no proven track record. When you have no experience and no capital to do stuff, you need to get them yourself. You need to build the experience and if it is possible, use that experience to build your capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my entire three years at university, I never traveled outside of London - except Brighton and Malaysia, if that counts! Instead, I spent my time building new skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Startup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;startup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From scratch, I studied graphic design, digital marketing, and business, realms that I never ventured into before and never thought I would prior to my startup project. After a while, I started marketing my skills to international clients via various online platforms and begin building my client base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that period, I slept only 5 hours a day and had a ton of caffeine - not really advisable for a uni student! Nevertheless, I survived, and although the project didn’t manage to launch in the end (we put it on hold as we weren’t satisfied with the final quality of the products), we definitely learned a lot from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have just launched another company with my partner, offering digital services to both local and international clients.  We hope that through this company we could eventually build up a core team that we trust as well as sufficient capital so that we could revisit our initial idea in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-Entrepreneurship-from-scratch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-Entrepreneurship-from-scratch/</guid>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>business</category>
        
        <category>networking</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Depression at University</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Depression.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;depression&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I noticed in Imperial is that depressed people tend to be quite evasive regarding their issues and are reluctant to admit they’re in trouble. In particular, people don’t want others to pity them and that contributes to the idea that depression is ‘taboo’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, from what I’ve seen, a lot of Imperial students suffer from it; what matters is how you handle it. People are often more than willing to help you, they do have similar feelings and can give you mental support if you need it. So don’t be afraid to voice out if you need help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when you do open up to someone else, they might not take it seriously as they don’t see the depth of how affected you are by it due to the mask that you put on daily, and the fact that you seem so ‘normal’. If you don’t feel comfortable talking with friends who may not know how to respond, Imperial health services do offer good professional counseling to those who need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Malaysian scholars, in particular, have very high expectations of themselves and being at a top university doesn’t really help matters! Here you’re surrounded by top-tier talent from all around the world, so if you fail at anything it hits you really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d say to always prepare yourself for failure; things don’t always turn out the way you want them to and that’s alright, you shouldn’t beat yourself up over it. Learn and salvage as much as possible from your mistake. Don’t dwell on it, work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;editors-note&quot;&gt;
Editor’s Note: Depression is a serious and complicated illness, and we would like to point out that depression can take many forms; experiences and symptoms stated here might differ with the experience of others that are experiencing depression, and the coping mechanisms that may work for one may not work as well for another person.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-Depression-at-university/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Wee-Rock-Depression-at-university/</guid>
        
        <category>depression</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[FULL] Conversations with Wee Rock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you say to your pre-university self?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of university are very different from high school. In high school or college, there was a defined set of targets and expectations put forward by others, for instance scoring well in school exams, looking for scholarship opportunities, entering a good university etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In university, you are on your own. You are responsible for every decision you make and every decision you make might decide who you are and what you do in the very near future. One major difference I noticed lies in the absence of short-term goals like what you would have during high school. You know you have to do something but what? How? I felt lost and perhaps depressed, to a certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Lost1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lost&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my second and third year, I started a few projects as well as some business endeavors. It was a tremendously exhausting journey but surprisingly I felt much better than I was in first year.  I found a path and a purpose, though it might not be the easiest path to walk on. I might trip or fall a lot but even if I do, I am moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some might say university is “useless” because in many cases, what you study will probably have nothing to do with what you do in the future. Personally, I think that university is the perfect ground for you to build connections with amazing people all around the world, and the perfect ground to fail. Yes, fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a university student, you do not have as many responsibilities and expectations than you would have as a working adult but you have more freedom and help. You can afford to fail and start over - an inevitable yet crucial process that builds you up to your eventual success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;University is the perfect ground for you to build connections with amazing people all around the world, and the perfect ground to fail. Yes, fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, you have an easy access to a network of professionals literally right at your doorstep! Professors and lecturers are generally always willing to help you if they can with free advice if you go up to them for a chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what was university like for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first entered university, I actually felt that the language and culture barrier was a factor that hindered social mingling, which was quite surprising to me. I assumed that it would go okay but I found it a bit challenging to mingle with the locals. To be frank, I found the local accent quite hard to understand; I connected better with international students and we knew how each other felt, since we were all trying our best to communicate and learn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the language and cultural barriers, I struggled a little in making deeper connections with people, even though I had no problem doing so back in Malaysia, but it did get better eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously I also felt lost as I was questioning what was the point of studying so hard in university. “What’s the next step?” I wondered, especially since I could see the end of university coming soon, and with that, there was a need to “step into society” and do something worthwhile as a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Due to the language and cultural barriers, I struggled a little in making deeper connections with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my second and third year, I felt a lot more comfortable. I eventually started some projects and a business of my own, which was quite ironic as I used to hate business. The financial pressure as a result of my business, the amount of workload from both study and work as well as personal health issues made me feel quite down in the dumps at a certain point. Some would say “depressed” although I’m not really sure if the symptoms fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this was the path I chose and I never regretted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you elaborate more on the “depression” aspect?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Depression.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;depression&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I noticed in Imperial is that depressed people tend to be quite evasive regarding their issues and are reluctant to admit they’re in trouble. In particular, people don’t want others to pity them and that contributes to the idea that depression is ‘taboo’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, from what I’ve seen, &lt;em&gt;a lot of Imperial students suffer from it&lt;/em&gt;; what matters is how you handle it. People are often more than willing to help you, they do have similar feelings and can give you mental support if you need it. So don’t be afraid to voice out if you need help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when you do open up to someone else, they might not take it seriously as they don’t see the depth of how affected you are by it due to the mask that you put on daily, and the fact that you seem so ‘normal’. If you don’t feel comfortable talking with friends who may not know how to respond, Imperial health services do offer good professional counseling to those who need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Malaysian scholars, in particular, have very high expectations of themselves and being at a top university doesn’t really help matters! Here you’re surrounded by top-tier talent from all around the world, so if you fail at anything it hits you really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d say to always prepare yourself for failure; things don’t always turn out the way you want them to and that’s alright, you shouldn’t beat yourself up over it. Learn and salvage as much as possible from your mistake. Don’t dwell on it, work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;editors-note&quot;&gt;Editor’s Note: Depression is a serious and complicated illness, and we would like to point out that depression can take many forms; experiences and symptoms stated here might differ with the experience of others that are experiencing depression, and the coping mechanisms that may work for one may not work as well for another person.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you elaborate more on the business that you started? I think it’d be helpful to give readers a glimpse of what is possible for them to accomplish even while they are at university.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a social enterprise with my business partner in Malaysia and recruited a few of my friends to join the team. The essence of a social entrepreneurship is building a business that gives back to the community, which I personally feel quite strongly about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you have no experience and no capital to do stuff, you need to get them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very rough in the beginning, especially when looking for investments or partnerships, as no one wants to support a company with no proven track record. When you have no experience and no capital to do stuff, you need to get them yourself. You need to build the experience and if it is possible, use that experience to build your capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my entire three years at university, I never traveled outside of London - except Brighton and Malaysia, if that counts! Instead, I spent my time building new skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Startup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;startup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From scratch, I studied graphic design, digital marketing, and business, realms that I never ventured into before and never thought I would prior to my startup project. After a while, I started marketing my skills to international clients via various online platforms and begin building my client base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that period, I slept only 5 hours a day and had a ton of caffeine - not really advisable for a uni student! Nevertheless, I survived, and although the project didn’t manage to launch in the end (we put it on hold as we weren’t satisfied with the final quality of the products), we definitely learned a lot from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have just launched another company with my partner, offering digital services to both local and international clients.  We hope that through this company we could eventually build up a core team that we trust as well as sufficient capital so that we could revisit our initial idea in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wow, that sounds great! Nice to hear from you, Wee Rock, and thank you for your time!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Conversations-with-Wee-Rock/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/10/01/Conversations-with-Wee-Rock/</guid>
        
        <category>university</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>business</category>
        
        <category>networking</category>
        
        <category>depression</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Quality at Imperial</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the academic field, rankings aren’t exactly synonymous with teaching quality. Imperial is amazing in terms of rankings, but in my opinion, the high rank comes mainly from the research and some of the teaching is honestly a bit subpar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect spoon-feeding, after all, it is the student’s responsibility to learn; I just think that certain members of the teaching staff could spend more energy connecting with students and presenting their knowledge with more passion. In my course, some of the students do indeed complain about the lecturers, and it’s not just a particular subset or even Malaysian mindset but it’s sort of agreed that we could have better teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their motivations for teaching are quite varied I’m sure, and I’m sure that a few of them likely wouldn’t even go into teaching if they were given a choice. In retrospect, I definitely gave a lot of educators some flak they didn’t deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Teaching-Quality-at-Imperial/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Teaching-Quality-at-Imperial/</guid>
        
        <category>university</category>
        
        <category>academic</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Studying the Wrong Course?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After coming out from university I feel like I chose the wrong course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Study.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Study&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out that I’m interested in Biology and Chemistry but those aren’t things I’m going to pursue as a career. In Biotechnology everything I learned is microscopic (for example, we learn about &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; and mosquito proteins and their inner workings/structural stuff) but my interest lies more towards bigger, more macro-level stuff on the scale of tissues and organs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I think the right course for me would have been biomedical science; I probably wouldn’t have been happier (the workload is crazy!) but I would definitely have liked what I studied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why didn’t you apply for that in the first place?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well for one I didn’t really realize how micro-focused the contents of the Biotechnology course was; another factor is that in the sixth form college I went to, Biomedical science is in a way the ‘dirty’ course in the sense that it is regarded as the course medicine rejects go to. Hence Biotech it was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have any major regrets about taking the course but it would be helpful to have that knowledge before starting the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is a difference between feeling the course is wrong for you and the course actually being really wrong for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s important for pre-uni students to know that just because you don’t feel comfortable studying a particular course, it doesn’t mean it is the wrong move for you; there is a difference between feeling the course is wrong for you and the course actually being really wrong for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though a few of our current batch applied to Oxbridge and got rejected, some of us have discussed it and agreed that although Oxbridge are really esteemed places of learning, in London you get an education more focused on networking potential alongside your study life, which really contributes to you having more contacts in various areas. Your network is your net worth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my misgivings I’m currently fairly satisfied as I feel in control of the path I am on, I am choosing where I am going. In university, I chose to invest in MNight (Malaysian Night) and other extracurricular activities and those were where I excelled in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Studying-the-Wrong-Course/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Studying-the-Wrong-Course/</guid>
        
        <category>regret</category>
        
        <category>biochemistry</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network = Networth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It really does not matter which university you go to, it’s the extracurricular activities and the people you meet with that determines the worth of your time spent there. The course is merely a channel to feed you information; I believe exams do not really teach me anything as its main role is to make me take the course seriously and connect people to the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Network.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could go to MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) or to Oxford or Cambridge but if you end up disinterested in the course while simultaneously not trying any new activities, you will only end up achieving less than if you had gone to a lesser-ranked uni and taken part in lots of extracurricular activities to broaden your horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you are connected with two friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is a very creative and proactive person; he really pushes himself to create things and has his own network of ‘makers’; by being friends with him you get the opportunity to hear about awesome things his friends are making and maybe even learn something new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another friend is a very friendly, outgoing person who volunteers a lot in her spare time. She likely has a network of contacts throughout say, education due to her experience volunteering there, and by being friends with her you also get access to her contacts in case you want to enter the field in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately for me, I have no regrets coming to London due to the network I have built up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Network-is-network/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Network-is-network/</guid>
        
        <category>networking</category>
        
        <category>extracurricular</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Mnight Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The main thing I have to say is that MNight is great but it WILL take up a lot of your time, and you need to be conscious of the pros and cons of joining it. MNight serves as an excellent entry point to learning and embodying &lt;em&gt;what it means to be Malaysian&lt;/em&gt; and shows the world what Malaysians have to offer in terms of what we stand for and what talents we have to offer (and boy do we see a lot of talent on display!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Malaysian.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malaysian&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flipside, however, something that doesn’t come up often about MNight is that involving yourself too heavily in it will effectively close the door off to many things you can do in terms of exploring other interests outside the Malaysian bubble (skydiving, mountaineering, and other sports, to name a few).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I would highly recommend it if you’re looking to develop a wide range of skills and especially your network; however, I think it’s worth considering joining in the first year and perhaps taking the second year to explore your options elsewhere, getting out of your comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an alumnus’ perspective, however, we definitely encourage you to come help out if you feel like you might want to give it a shot, as we definitely need brilliant people to helm various positions (choreographers, committee members, ushers and etc.) to help out the next batch of first years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some people have commented that Imperial’s MNight, in particular is somewhat different in terms of content, with a lot of emphasis on themes and settings more often portrayed in mainstream media as opposed to more culturally accurate settings for example. Would you say that’s true?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think that is one way of putting it; Imperial’s MNight has always tried to keep our content original, engaging and universal, and places a heavy emphasis on showcasing our greatest resource: talent. We also try to insert universal themes featuring more universal and ‘primal’ emotions such as love, romance, betrayal and friendship as well as interesting plot twists to keep it relatable for the international crowd, which I’m quite glad to say Imperial does a good job of attracting every year so everyone can enjoy the play! I think it’s a great way of representing spirit, cultural idiosyncrasies, and traditions; would definitely recommend you giving it a try!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-My-MNight-Experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-My-MNight-Experience/</guid>
        
        <category>MNight</category>
        
        <category>Malaysia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join MNight lah!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you had to sell MNight to a potential fresher in a few sentences, what would you say?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I would like to preface this by saying that although some points can apply to MNights across the United Kingdom, I primarily refer to the Imperial experience of MNight as this is what I have experienced.  Other universities likely have different scales and individual experiences unique to their performances. Okay, on to business!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, you can train a boatload of skills (time management, leadership, discipline to name a few of the common ones) just via ONE event, especially if you intend to become a choreographer. It looks great on your CV and you WILL get a chance to expand on existing skills and learn new ones. Some of the previous Malaysians found they could sing and act during MNight; you also get to try new things like ballroom dancing alongside your Malaysian friends, in a non-judgemental and somewhat familiar setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kualistories.github.io/img/Dance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, you get the chance to showcase Malaysian talent on a global platform. I personally feel Imperial does a great job of being internationally friendly as our themes are very relatable across borders. When you’re on the stage, you’re not only representing yourself but also Msoc (to the other societies), Imperial (to the other unis) and most importantly Malaysia (to the world!) You’re essentially a window or a gateway into Malaysia, and when Imperial graduates talk about university this performance is likely something they’ll still remember after they graduate, so you definitely can achieve an impact. These 2 nights alone can shape the impressions of 1200 people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MSoc (Malaysian society) is basically a ready-made friendship circle for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly and finally, you get to meet a whole lot of different people in a very easy way. MSoc (Malaysian society) is basically a ready-made friendship circle for you; learning new activities together has been proven to be a really effective way to bond and get new friends in a new environment, which can help you find your footing when you first arrive here in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, here in Imperial, you will find that we really emphasize a high quality of production; this culture of wanting to be the best can and will propel you to achieve more than you would think possible. Your seniors and your seniors’ seniors have experienced and put on their own high-quality performances and will push you to your very limits; so it is definitely a tough but worthy endeavor to involve yourselves in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Join-MNight-lah/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kualistories.github.io/2017/09/10/Nick-Oon-Join-MNight-lah/</guid>
        
        <category>MNight</category>
        
        <category>Malaysia</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
